Guide to the Charles Thomas Andrews papers,1840-1922.
Andrews, Charles Thomas papers,1840-1922.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Charles Thomas Andrews papers, 1840-1922.
2180
Charles Thomas Andrews, 1842-1931.
2.2 cubic ft.
Scrapbooks, correspondence, broadsides, pamphlets, historical sketches, clippings, addresses, manuscripts, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Annotated scrapbooks include correspondence, broadsides, pamphlets, historical sketches, addresses, clippings, and editorials relating to his positions, and to Republican and Progressive Party politics, conditions in Cuba and Puerto Rico, education and welfare of New York Indians, and genealogical data on Andrews and Clark families. Also, correspondence, addresses, manuscript essays, school newspapers, and other printed items.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Charles T. Andrews was a teacher in Watkins Glen, Jacksonville, Reynoldsville, and North Hector, New York, and Owatonna, Minnesota, also an employee of newspapers in Watkins Glen and South Bend, Illinois; he later served as a school commissioner of Schuyler County; Seneca Falls school superintendent; agent of New York Secretary of State supervising absentee voting of soldiers in Cuba and Puerto Rico, 1899; Inspector of State Schools, 1900-1904.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Annotated scrapbooks include correspondence, broadsides, pamphlets, historical sketches, addresses, clippings, and editorials relating to his positions, and to Republican and Progressive Party politics, conditions in Cuba and Puerto Rico, education and welfare of New York Indians, and genealogical data on Andrews and Clark families. Also, correspondence, addresses, manuscript essays, school newspapers, and other printed items.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Andrews, Charles Thomas, 1842-1931.; Andrews family.; Clark family.
Subjects:
Family--New York (State); Education--New York (State); Indians of North America--New York (State); Journalism.
Places:
Cuba.; Puerto Rico.; New York (State)--Politics and government.
Form and Genre Terms:
Broadsides.; Genealogies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Letter to Mary Andrews from Uncle William's wife Elmina (Andrews), son Horace and daughter Maria, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Legal documents - Andrews and others, 1854-1864 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Legal documents - Andrews and others, 1867-1878 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Andrews family letters, 1864-1899 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Andrews family letters, 1900-1908 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Andrews family letters, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Andrews family letters, 1910-1915 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Andrews family letters, 1919-1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Andrews family letters, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lulu Andrews' school literary paper, "The Evening Star", Jan. 15, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Poems written by Charles Andews for Mary, 1909, 1915, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Arthur Andrews letters, 1892, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Jan.-June 1894 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Arthur Andrews letters, July-Sept. 1894 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Oct. 1894 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Nov.-Dec. 1894 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Jan.-Mar. 1895 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Apr.-June 1895 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Aug.-Sept. 1895 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Oct.-Dec. 1895 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Jan.-Apr. 1896 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Arthur Andrews letters, May-July 1896 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Aug.-Oct. 1896 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Nov.-Dec. 1896 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Jan.-May 1897 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Arthur Andrews letters, June-Dec. 1897 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Jan.-Apr. 1898 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Arthur Andrews letters, May-Sept. 1898 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Oct.-Dec. 1898 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Jan.-Mar. 1899 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Apr.-May 1899 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Arthur Andrews letters, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Arthur Andrews letters, 1901-1902 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Jan.-Aug. 1903 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Sept.-Dec. 1903 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Arthur Andrews letters, Jan.-Apr. 1904 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Arthur Andrews letters, June-Dec. 1904 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Arthur Andrews letters, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Arthur Andrews letters, 1906-1907 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Arthur Andrews letters, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Arthur Andrews letters, n.d., incomplete (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Photographs of Arthur Andrews, 1906, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Bosworth genealogy, 1738-1868 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Clark family notes, 1809-1851 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Charles Andrews: school essays as pupil in district school, 1854-1861 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Essay on "The Soul" by C. Andrews, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Philoputhean Journal, Nov. 3, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Philoputhean Journal, Dec. 8, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Philoputhean Journal, Dec. 12, 1860, Mar. 9, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- "A Glance at Contemporaneous History," by C. Andrews, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Educational lecture at Owatonna, Minn. by C. Andrews, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Partial index of the copies of the Watkins, NY Express bound in the cover "Charles T. Andrews Papers - Watkins Express", 1872-1873 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Arthur Andrews' letters printed in the Seneca County Courier (newsclippings) (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Scrapbook pages of "Letters from the West", ca. 1897, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "Garden of Eden," by C. Andrews, ca. 1910 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- "True Lincoln Story" while on magazine, South Indiana, ca. 1905 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- "Golden Wedding" of Charles and Mary Andrews, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "Mother" (Mary Andrews' death) by C. Andrews, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous writings by C. Andrews (Box 4, Folder 8)
- C. Andrews: School Commissioners papers, 1873-1879 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- C. Andrews: School Commissioners Record Book, 1873-1875 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Mynderse Commencement Address by C. Andrews, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Mynderse Commencement Address by C. Andrews, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- School address by C. Andrews, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Mss. of school addresses - Plattsburg Normal, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- "The Seneca County Courier," "Centennial of the Schools", Apr. 11, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- "Hector Township in the Military Tract - Then and Now" by C. Andrews (Box 5, Folder 8)
- "Hector - Then and Now" by C. Andrews (Box 5, Folder 9)
- "New Harmony - The Seed Bed of Modern Progress" by C. Andrews (Box 5, Folder 10)
- "Evolution of the Wheeled Vehicle" (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Indian Orphan School (Box 5, Folder 12)
- The Andrews Number Charts (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Articles (newsclippings) (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Andrews family clippings (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Editorials possible for Eagle May by C. Andrews (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Podunk (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Schuyler County History (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Alexander Hamilton Political Parties (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Miscellaneous writings (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 22-23)
- Newsclippings (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Volumes (all by Charles T. Andrews unless otherwise noted)
  - Watkins 1860 F F Minn., 1864-1868 (Box 6)
  - Watkins, 1876-1879, 1873-1916 (Box 6)
  - Family and Friends Scrap Book, 1882-1918 (Box 6)
  - Cuba and Porto Rico in 1899, 1899 (Box 6)
  - South Bend, Indiana Scrap Book, 1913, 1891, 1913-1922 (Box 7)
  - Indians of New York State (scrapbook), 1902-1911 (Box 7)
  - Autobiographic Notes, ca. 1916 (Box 7)
  - Andrews Family Accounts, 1874-1881 (Box 7)
  - Andrews Family Accounts, 1864-1874 (Box 7)
  - Charles T. Andrews Diary, 1877 (1900-1905) (Box 7)
  - Charles T. Andrews Diary, 1864-1874 (Box 7)
  - Churches and Pastors of Seneca County, N.Y. compiled and published by Courier Printing Company, Seneca Falls, NY, 1896 (Box 7)
  - "Grip's" Historical Sourvenir of Seneca Falls, ca. 1904 (?) (Box 7)
  - Richard Andrews Accounts, 1836- (Box 7)
  - The Two Orphans of Marrakech and Other Dramatic Spots, by David Dunham, inscribed by the author to Prof. and Mrs. Andrews, 1935 (Box 7)